What the hell's going on?
どうなってんだ クソ
魔女教のしわざか？
Is this the Witch Cult's doing?
Hey! Anyone?
おい 誰か 誰かいねーのかよ！
Is anyone there?
Answer me!
返事してくれー！
Wh-What's this overpowering smell?
何だ この強烈なにおい
P-Patrasche!
パ… パトラッシュ…
No...
違う…
A flower like this couldn't actually exist.
こんな花は 現実にはありえない
And Patrasche wouldn't just let me die...
俺を見殺しにする パトラッシュも
Which means... This is an illusion.
つまり これは… 幻影
It's all make-believe!
全部 まやかしだ！
You're that lesser spirit.
Did you come back to help me?
微精霊
お前 また俺を助けて… あっ
（ユリウス･ユークリウス）スバル
Subaru!
What, it's you?
お前かよ
That spiteful tone tells me
it is without a doubt you.
（ユリウス）
その憎まれ口は
君で間違いないようだな
I cannot imagine my subconscious
よもや 私の意識下の君が―
creating such a realistic imitation of you.
ここまで本物を再現できるとは
思えないからね
They're all under a bewitching spell.
幻惑系の術だ
As of now, only you and I
have returned to normal.
今は 私と君の２人だけしか
戻ってきていない
How did you make it back?
どうやって戻ってきた
I burned a flower in my illusion.
幻覚の中で 花を焼いた
I see.
なるほど
Someone layered the flower's scent with hypnosis.
花の香りに
暗示の術式を乗せたのか
Hey, is that...
お前 それって…
The glow of my little buds.
（ユリウス）
我がつぼみたちの輝きだよ
I'm about to teach everyone how to break out of the bewitching spell.
今から 全員に
幻惑の破り方を伝える
In... Nes.
イン ネス
Hi-ho! Hi-ho! No one's here! Where am I!?
I've strayed away... No, we've been pulled apart!
Is his affinity too great?
（ユリウス）
親和性が高すぎるのか？
すまない 深呼吸して耐えてくれ
This is bad! If I don't do something...
I'm sorry. Take a deep breath and endure it.
No, this is awful! No matter how much
forest I destroy, nothin' changes!
For this to happen at a time
like this... Crusch-sama!
I cannot spare the energy
to fine-tune it just for you.
今は 君だけのために
調律する余裕がない
Bringing everyone back is our top priority.
全員を引き戻すのが優先だ
That will be quite enough.
（ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレア）
そこまでにして頂こう
Just kill me.
（ラム）
殺しなさい 辱めは受けないわ
Do not humiliate me any further.
And? What is the meaning of all this?
（ラム）
それで これは
どういうつもりなのか―
You'll explain it to me, won't you, Balse?
説明してくれるんでしょうね
バルス
That's what I'd like to ask you.
そりゃ こっちのセリフだろ
You're the one who attacked us first.
お前が先制攻撃
仕掛けてきたんじゃねえか
What were you thinking?
どういうつもりだ
You shouldn't have to ask what I was thinking.
（ラム）
どういうつもりも 何もないわ
It's rich, coming from an ingrate like you.
恩知らずのバルスが
よく言えたものね
Ingrate?
恩知らず？
You are, aren't you?
だってそうでしょ
After everything Roswaal-sama did for you...
あれだけロズワール様に
多大な恩を受けておきながら―
Once you're done with him, you'd rush to wag your tail for another master.
用済みと見るや
すぐに別の主人に尻尾を振る
Hold up! I think you're
confusing your stories here!
待てよ 何か話が食い違ってるぞ
So this is what it means to bite
the hand that feeds you.
飼い犬に手を噛(か)まれるとは
このことね
Listen to me... What about the handwritten letter?
聞けよ
親書だ　そのために
手紙を書いたはずだ
We wrote you a letter about this!
Wasn't it delivered to the mansion?
屋敷に届いてないか？
Yes, we did get a letter from the capital,
（ラム）
確かに 王都から
手紙は届いた　でも―
but...
It was quite amusing, sending us a blank letter.
白紙の親書だなんて―
随分と面白い趣向が
あったもんだわ
A blank letter?
（スバル）白紙の親書？
To send a blank letter
白紙の書状を送ることは―
is a metaphor that means you have no intention of speaking to the recipient.
相手に対話する
意思がないことを知らせる―
暗喩として用いられる
It could easily be interpreted
as a declaration of war.
宣戦布告と受け取られても
しかたがない
This is a huge misunderstanding!
とんだ勘違いだ
Do I even look that clever to you?
そもそも 俺がそんな
悪賢く見えるか？
So this is what it means to bite
the hand that feeds you.
飼い犬に手を噛まれるとは
このことね
You're still saying that?
まだ言う！
I can't say it enough.
（ラム）
言い足りないぐらいよ
でも おおよそ分かったわ
But I get the gist now.
The blank letter was some kind of mistake,
白紙の親書は 何かの手違いで―
and you are still Emilia-sama's dog.
バルスまだ エミリア様の犬
それでいいのね
Correct?
Not really, but...
よくねえけど…
Okay, sure. Dogs are like family, anyway.
いいよ
犬は家族みたいなもんだし
エミリアのなら 犬でもいい
As long as I'm Emilia's dog, fine by me.
Would you not say that standard is a bit low?
それは さすがに
志が低くありませんかな
In any case, these guys are reinforcements.
とにかくこの人たちは
援軍 味方だ
They're friends.
We pulled them together
to wipe out the Witch Cult.
魔女教の奴らをぶっ飛ばすために
集まってもらったんだよ
There's no time.
時間がねえ
まずは村人たちの避難からだ
We need to start by evacuating the villagers.
Subaru, they seem rather uneasy.
スバル どうやら
彼らは不安がっている
Remember to be considerate.
配慮を忘れずに
Okay, attention!
はーい 注目
I haven't seen you guys in a while.
How have you been?
みんな 久しぶりだけど
元気してた？
Look, I know this is sudden,
いきなりなんだけど
今日はみんなにお願いがあるんだ
but I need to ask you all a favor!
It seems witchfiends are up to
no good in the nearby forest again.
実は この辺りの森で
また魔獣が悪さしてるらしい
So I've brought some specialists
to exterminate them.
で それを駆除するための
業者を連れてきたんだけど―
But while they're doing their thing,
みんなには 作業の間
村を離れててほしい
I'd like you all to leave the village.
Don't try to fool us!
（青年団長）
ごまかさないでくださいよ
You're trying to sound cheerful about this,
but the villagers are frightened!
スバル様は
わざと明るく言いますけど―
村のみんなはおびえてる！
We've always feared the Witch Cult
would try something!
魔女教が 何かするんじゃ
ないかって ずっと！
The Witch Cult? No one told me about that.
（ケティ）
魔女教だって？ 聞いてねえぞ
Hey, wait...
（村人Ａ）おいおい
（村人Ｂ）マジか
Seriously?
Why lie about that?
（村人Ｃ）
どうして ウソつくんだ
Maybe he's trying to hide something.
（村人Ｄ）
何か隠してるんじゃないのか
So you're not going to deny it?
（青年団長）
否定 してくれないんですね
（村人Ｅ）
やっぱり本当だったんだ！
That must mean it was true!
Why would they bother a remote village like this?
（村人Ｆ）
何で こんなへんぴな村に
Why else? Because of that damn half-elf!
（村人Ｇ）
決まってるじゃないか
ハーフエルフのせいだ！
Because this domain's lord
is endorsing that half-elf for ruler!
（村人Ｈ）
領主様が ハーフエルフを
王様に推薦なんてするから！
Why do you have to make it about that?
（スバル）
何でそうなるんだよ
The half-elf thing...
ハーフエルフは…
Emilia has nothing to do with it!
エミリアは関係ないだろ！
She has everything to do with it!
関係ないわけないだろ！
If you mess with a half-elf,
the Witch Cult starts stirring up trouble.
ハーフエルフに関わったら
魔女教が暴れだす！
Even the village children know that!
そんなの 村の子供だって
知ってるんだ！
You guys seriously believe that?
みんな 本気でそう思ってるのか
That it's the fault of the half-elf in the mansion!?
全部 屋敷の
ハーフエルフのせいだって！
The village, huh?
（エミリア）村か…
It might cause you trouble if we're seen together.
でも 私が一緒だと―
スバルの迷惑に
なるかもしれなくて…
Does that mean I'm just being selfish again?
これも俺の身勝手だって
そういうことなのか…
（フェリックス･アーガイル）
顔 上げる
"Lift your head. Don't look down."
下を向くなって
クルシュ様なら絶対言うから
That's what Crusch-sama would say.
You...
お前…
Do you think what you're doing is wrong?
自分のしたこと
間違ってると思ったの？
If not, there's no reason to look down.
思ってないなら
うつむく必要なんてない
Or is it harder to lift your head here
それとも
ここで顔を上げるのは―
than to throw a tantrum in the castle?
お城で無謀なたんか
切るよりも 大変？
Come on, now...
あのなあ…
You're right.
そうだな　あの時と比べたら
へでもねえや
Compared to that, this is nothing!
I understand your feelings and concerns very well!
みんなの気持ちも訴えも
よーく分かった
I won't tell you to try to change them now.
今すぐ それを―
どうこうしてくれなんて
言ったりしない
Obviously, you'll have your own opinions.
みんなにも考えがあって当然だ
It hurts, but I understand.
痛いけど それが分かったよ
But for now, please accept my request.
だけど 今は飲み込んでくれ
今は従ってくれ！
Please do as I say!
Staying in the village is dangerous.
村にいるのは危ないんだ 本当に
That's the truth!
The words of an employee of our household
（ラム）
当家の使用人の言葉は―
are those of our master, Roswaal-sama, himself.
領主である ロズワール様の
ご命令そのものよ
Ram...
ラム
Follow his instructions immediately.
早々に指示に従いなさい
You saved me back there. Thanks.
（スバル）
さっきは助かった　ありがとよ
But...
けど
What?
何？
Having you take my side so easily
is a new kind of feeling.
お前が素直に
俺の味方してくれたのが―
何か新鮮で
Does that mean you've acknowledged me?
認めてくれたってこと？
フン！
Subaru!
（ペトラ）スバル！
よう ペトラ　どうした？
Hey, Petra... What's up?
U-Um, will the lady from
the mansion run away with us?
あ… あの… お屋敷のお姉ちゃんも
一緒に逃げるの？
Huh?
She came to the village yesterday.
（ペトラ）
昨日 お姉ちゃんが村に来たの
She told us we should hide away in the mansion
お姉ちゃん
スバルと同じように―
ここは危ないから お屋敷に
避難してって言ってくれたの
because it's dangerous here, just like you said.
But no one in the village would listen to her.
でも 村のみんなは
誰も聞いてくれなくて
It's okay.
（スバル）大丈夫だ
あの子は 別に怒ったりしないから
She wouldn't get mad about something like that.
Anyway, you should hurry and run.
それより 早く逃げな
Okay!
What happened to Emilia after that?
（スバル）
エミリアは その後どうした
You should know that she isn't
so perceptive as to back down
（ラム）
否定されて すぐに引き下がるほど
物分かりがよい方でないのは―
the moment someone denies her.
バルスも知っているでしょ
But I also know she's not the kind of girl
who can just shrug off being badmouthed.
でも 邪険にされて傷つかない―
女の子じゃないってことも
知ってるんだぜ
She tried to convince the villagers
to leave, but they refused.
村人たちを説得して 断られて―
But she couldn't stand idly by,
それでも じっとして
いられなくて―
so she reinforced the forest barrier.
森の結界を
結び直したりしていたわ
She feared there might be a witchfiend attack.
魔獣の可能性を危惧したのね
In and of itself, that's not
a bad decision, but still...
それは それで
悪い判断ではないんだけどな
Julius.
（スバル）ユリウス
一緒に来てくれ
Come with me.
I'm going to explain things to Emilia
and the loli in the mansion.
屋敷にいるエミリアとロリに
説明しに行く
With you there, it'll be more convincing.
お前が俺の隣にいるのと
いないのとじゃ―
説得力が違う
Just take it as a sign of my repentance
for going nuts in the castle.
おとなしく 城でやらかした俺の
反省の証になれ
（ユリウス）
なるほど 了解した
I see. Understood.
If that will help the discussion
proceed more smoothly,
それで 話が円滑に
進むのであれば―
do not hesitate to use me.
遠慮なく利用するといい
Also...
それと―
You were the one who put
a spirit on me, weren't you?
俺に精霊くっつけてたのは
お前だよな
Explain that.
ちゃんと説明しておけ
I get that you're a spirit arts user.
お前が 精霊使いだってことぐらい
分かってる
More precisely, I prefer
to be called a "spirit knight."
正確には 精霊騎士と
呼んでほしいな
I do use the spirit arts, of course.
精霊術はもちろんだが―
But that has not prevented me
from training with the sword.
剣のほうの修練にも
手を抜いた覚えはないのでね
And you were the one who planted
the little red one on me?
で あの赤い子に
俺を見張らせてたってわけか
"Planted it on you" is a harsh way to put it.
（ユリウス）
見張らせていたとは 心外だな
I was only having her, Ia, secretly protect you.
彼女―
イアには 陰ながら君を
保護してもらっていたのさ
By the way, what was that thing you did
when you broke the illusion?
ちなみに 幻覚破りの時の
あれは何だったんだ
A high class of magic known as "Nect."
高等魔法の一種である ネクトだ
It connects the gates of all who are in range,
範囲内の人間どうしの
ゲートをつなぎ―
意思疎通を可能とする
so they can communicate with each other.
However, it appeared to work
a bit too well on you.
少々 君には
効き目が強すぎたようだったが
I thought I was about to lose myself.
俺が俺じゃなくなるかと思った
For the spirits to mistake the tuning is unusual.
（ユリウス）
彼女らが調律を見誤るのは珍しい
It seems to me that you may have
a strong affinity with spirits.
ひょっとすると君は 精霊との
親和性が高いのかもしれないな
Sadly, the only spirit I ever
made friends with was a gray cat.
あいにく 俺が仲よくした精霊は
ネズミ色した猫だけだよ
（フェリックス）
で？ ユリウスと
ちゃんと仲直りした？
Well? Did you patch things up with Julius?
Did it work out?
できた？
I'm taking that matter back with me,
（スバル）
その件については―
to mull over carefully before
I make an optimistic decision.
持ち帰って検討したうえで
前向きに善処するとして
Come to the mansion with me.
お前も 屋敷まで一緒に来てくれ
I'll need at least one person
from the Crusch camp with me,
親書の件の誤解を
スムーズに解くために―
to smooth over the misunderstanding
with the letter.
クルシュ陣営の人間が
１人は必要だ
I'll do that after I finish my work here.
それは こっちの仕事が
終わってからね
Subaru-kyun, come help us too.
スバルきゅんも手伝って
It's dangerous work involving the Witch Cult.
魔女教絡みの危険な仕事
積み荷を言い値で買い取るって
契約なんだから―
The contract said he'd buy
their cargo at the asking price,
so we must thoroughly inspect the goods.
きちんと 中身の
検分もしないとねー
Huh? But that shouldn't be our job.
は？ それは俺たちの
仕事じゃねえだろ
Isn't this more importa—
それより こっちのほうが…
Oh, come on!
いいから いいから
Whoa, hold up now.
No lovers' quarrels in my carriage!
人の竜車で 痴話ゲンカなんて
始めんじゃねえ
Hee-hee! You got in trouble, Subaru-kyun!
（フェリックス）
ププー スバルきゅんたら
怒られてやんの！
Really, what a troublemaker!
もう ホント困っちゃうよねー
There. You let your guard down.
はい 油断した
This guy's a member of the Witch Cult.
（フェリックス）
この人 魔女教徒だよ
さっき触って確認したの
I touched him earlier to make sure of it.
A weird spell is implanted in him,
just like the "fingers" of that Sin Archbishop.
大罪司教の指先と同じ
変な術式が埋め込まれてる
One was among the merchants?
（スバル）
行商人に紛れてたのか？
That's why I stole into his carriage,
to get under his guard.
だから 油断させようと思って
竜車に乗り込んだわけ
Now, tell us all the details
concerning what you're plotting.
さあ 何を企(たくら)んでたのか
洗いざらい 吐いてちょうだい
My hands are the gentlest in the world,
フェリちゃんの手は
世界一優しい手だけど―
but they can do some nasty things too.
ひどいこともできるんだからね
That's...
（ケティ）…ス
何？
What?
right.
デス
Ia!
イア その子を守れ！
（ケティ）さあ 終わりの始まり…
Protect him!
And now, it's the beginning of the end! Boom!
デス！
Thank goodness... You're awake.
よかった 気がついたみたいだね
Why are... you dressed like that?
（スバル）お前… その格好
（フェリックス）
しかたないでしょ 服は
治癒魔法で再生できないもん
It's not like I want to be.
I can't regenerate clothes with healing magic.
ともあれ この状況の中
君もフェリスも無事でよかった
Regardless, given the situation,
I'm glad you and Ferris are all right.
Run 'em off! Don't back down!
奴ら どっから村に…
How did they get into the village?
竜車の積み荷だったんだよ
They stowed away in the carriages.
行商人に指先がいたのに
対処しきれなかった
There was a finger among the merchants,
and we didn't take care of him.
私の失敗
I failed.
This is not the time for regrets.
今は 悔やんでいる時ではない
負傷者は ティビーと
ラム女史と共に―
We had Tivey and Madame Ram evacuate
to the mansion with the injured.
屋敷に避難させている
Ferris, join them and heal who you can.
フェリス 君も合流して治療を
分かった
Got it.
Okay, let's crush all the fingers that are left!
よし こっちは
残る指先を全部潰すぞ！
To think, to think, to think, to think!
（指先）
まさか まさかまさか まさか！
That you would resist us this much!
これほどまでに あらがうとは！
Such tenacity, clinging to
this ever-increasing love...
（指先）
これほど数を増す 我が寵(ちょう)愛に―
なお 食いつく執念！
As a diligent disciple,
I cannot begin to express my respect.
勤勉の使徒として
さあ勤勉に 絶えないのデス
Ah! My brain trembles!
ああ！ 脳が震えるー！
You're mine.
（ヴィルヘルム）取った
In battle, if one focuses
on what the unseen arm does,
見えない腕の戦い方に
注視すれば―
one will fail to see what is visible.
見えるものは おろそかになる
That is sloth, yes?
怠惰デス ね
Yes.
デス
自爆したか
He self-destructed.
（スバル）ヴィルヘルムさん
Wilhelm-san!
We can't leave him like this.
このままじゃヤバイ
フェリスの所に連れてかねえと
We've gotta get him to Ferris!
Why?
（指先）なぜ
Why? Why? Why? Why? Why? Why!?
なぜなぜなぜなぜ
なぜなぜ なーぜ！
Why are you still alive?
なぜ あなた まだ存命なのデスか？
After all the abuse you've suffered... Why!?
あれだけの仕打ちを受け なお
なぜ！
Why do you not bend to my diligence!?
我が勤勉の前に
屈しないのデスかー！
At a time like this too...
It's just one after another!
このタイミングで
次から次へと！
Hey, look here!
おい 見ろ！
お前の捜し物は これだろ
This is what you're looking for, right?
It's a gift from your precious witch.
大好きな魔女様からの 贈り物だ
（指先）
あー この盗人(ぬすっと)が！
You thief!
You really did have it!
やはり 貴様が
持っていたのデスか！
Quit shouting...
どなるなよ
あんまり怒られると アレだ―
If you keep yelling at me like that,
it'll make my brain tremble.
脳が震える
死ぬがいい―
You must die.
デス！
Now!
Julius, I'll work things out here somehow.
ユリウス こっちは何とかする
あとは そっちで何とかしろ
You handle things on your end.
And take care of Wilhelm-san!
ヴィルヘルムさんを頼んだ
That is quite a vague order,
なんとも曖昧な指示だが 了解した
but very well.
ユリウス… いや あとでな！
Julius...
Actually, it can wait!
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
（指先）
待て待て待て待て
待て待て待て 待つのデス
Wait, right there!
You cowardly, foolish, insolent, little man!
この卑劣 愚劣な 不埒漢(ふらちかん)があ！
No matter where you try to run, it's futile.
どこへ逃げてもムダなのデス
What do you expect to find
at wherever you're running to?
（指先）
逃げた先に
何があるというのデス？
At long last, it would seem the end has come!
いよいよもって
終わりの時がきたようデス！
これ 何だか分かるか
Do you know what this is?
結界用の魔石だよ
It's a magic stone for creating barriers.
森中のあちこちの木に
仕込んであった
They were stashed in trees
throughout the forest.
You didn't notice?
気づかなかったか？
あなた 一体 何を？
What are you talking about?
（スバル）
この辺りは 魔獣の群生地
俺たちは格好のエサだ
This area is a witchfiend breeding ground,
and we're a prime feast for them.
At least, if you don't have
one of Emilia's barrier stones!
エミリアの
この結界石がなけりゃな！
残る指先は あと１本
そいつさえ 片づければ
Only one finger left now.
Once we get rid of that one...
Damn... There's no time to waste.
クッソー 急がねえと
Ah!
My!
いやー ハハハハ…
Ah! My brain trembles!
（指先）
ああー 脳が震えるー
Sloth!
（スバル）怠惰ー！
That's enough, villain.
（エミリア）そこまでよ 悪党
Emilia...
エミリア…
Stand down, villain.
下がりなさい 悪党
こんなひどいことをして
私は許さない！
I won't stand for your wicked deeds!
A-Ah... Ah! How grand!
ああ ああ ああ 何と―
何とよき日 何という吉日
何という宿命ー！
What a grand day! What a lucky day!
What a grand destiny!
エミリア！
Emilia!
（フェリックス）待った
Wait!
I... I can't wait around now!
待ってる場合じゃねえだろ
You want to make Emilia fight him!?
エミリアと
あいつを戦わせるつもりか！
Calm down.
落ち着いて
少しは信用してあげなよ
Have a little faith in her.
The people you want to protect
君が 守りたいって
思ってる人が―
ただ後ろにいるだけの人じゃ
ないってこと
aren't always as helpless as you think.
Oh, my witch!
（指先）
おーおー 魔女よー
My witch! My love's guide!
魔女よ 我が愛の道しるべよ
（パック）
自慢のまな娘に
見ほれるのは分かるけど―
I don't blame you for being
charmed by my beloved daughter,
but I won't allow any
unwanted pests around her!
悪い虫はお断りだよ！
Naïve!
甘い！
Naïve! Naïve! Naïve! Naïve! Naïve, naïve,
naïve, naïve, naïve, naïve! So very naïve!
甘い甘い甘い甘いまいまいまい
まいまいまいまいまい…
デス！
これぞ 寵愛の結末
我が愛の成果
This is love's true ending...
The fruit of my love.
Proof that the witch has returned my love!
私の愛に 魔女が
答えた証なのデス！
That proof doesn't exist.
そんな証 ないから
Your crush is purely one-sided.
君の完全な片思い！
Yes!
（指先）デス！
ああー これは実に 実に勤勉デス
Ah, this is true... true diligence.
フフハハハ…
Thank you for being defeated.
ありがとう ちゃんとやられて
（フェリックス）
ね？ 言ったとおりでしょ
See? Didn't I tell you?
（ユリウス）
これで指先は全滅した
私たちの勝利だ
We've now eliminated all the fingers.
Victory is ours.
It's finally over...
（スバル）
やっと終わった…
Get over there.
会っといでよ
R-Right...
Subaru-kyun?
スバルきゅん？
I have to get away.
（スバル）
離れないと
エミリアから みんなから
From Emilia... From everyone...
Subaru-kyun, where are you going?
（フェリックス）
スバルきゅん どこ行くの？
Stay away!
（スバル）近づくな！
I'm...
俺は…
スバル
Subaru...
Julius, stay away from—
（スバル）
ユリウス 俺から離れ…
You're too late.
ても遅いのデス
The moment Ia was flung from his body,
I had a bad feeling...
イアが 突然スバルの身から
はじかれた時点で―
イヤな予感はしていたが
What do you mean?
どういうこと？
あれは スバルではない
That
isn't Subaru.
（スバル）
そう 私は魔女教 大罪司教
“怠惰”担当―
That's right.
I am a Sin Archbishop in the Witch Cult.
Archbishop of Sloth,
ペテルギウス･ロマネコンティ
Petelgeuse Romanée-Conti, at your service!
デス！
Fantastic!
実にいい！
What a fantastic body this is!
実に すばらしい体デス
It's been decades since I had
a body that fit me so well!
これほどなじむ体は
何十年ぶりか！
狂人め！
You madman!
Get out of that body right now!
今すぐ その体から出ていけ！
Madman?
狂人？
そう 私は
愛の狂気にいるのデス ヒヒ…
That's right. I am driven mad with love.
慈愛に 敬愛に 純愛に
情愛に 親愛に 聖愛に 友愛に
Generous love, respectful love, pure love,
tender love, familial love,
erotic love, friendly love!
愛に愛に愛に愛愛愛愛…
Love, love, love... Love! Love! Love! Love!
Love!
愛ー！
Subaru! Wake up!
（ユリウス）
スバル！ 目を覚ますんだ！
（スバル）ムダデス
It's no use.
すでに 肉体の制御は
私の意識下にあるのデス
This body is already under
my subconscious control.
Come to your senses, Subaru!
Realize what you're about to do.
気づけ スバル！
自分が何をしようとしているのかを
Remember what you returned here to do!
何のために ここまで
戻ってきたのかを思い出せ！
What, you say?
（スバル）何デス 何が…
And what was—
Get the hell out of my head, moron!
あったもクソもあるか バカ野郎！
I am Petelgeuse Romanée-Conti...
俺は…
ペテルギウス･ロマネコンティ
This body has already become my finger.
この身 すでに私の指先
Shut up! I'm Natsuki Subaru!
黙れ！ 俺は
ナツキ･スバルだー！
Kill me, Julius.
やってくれ ユリウス
お前の その剣で
Take your sword, and...
What are you saying, Subaru?
何を言い出すんだ スバル！
If you don't stop me now, we can't win.
（スバル）
今 俺を止めなきゃ 勝てなくなる
Before that happens...
その前に
No, Subaru! I cannot do that!
ダメだ スバル　それはできない
“あとでな”と君は言った！
You told me, "It can wait."
Wasn't there something you meant to tell me?
私に 何か話すことが
あったんじゃないのか！
Sorry... It looks like I won't get the chance.
悪かった それ
話せそうにねえわ
Ferris!
フェリス
頼む
Please.
You can resent me for this, Subaru-kun.
恨んでいいよ スバルくん
私も恨むから
I'll resent myself too.
フェリス！
Ferris!
No one else can do it, can they?
（フェリックス）
ほかの誰にもできないでしょ
This is what Subaru-kyun wants!
スバルきゅんの
これが望みだよ！
But still...
だからといって…
You think I did that because I wanted to?
（フェリックス）
私が 喜んで
やったと思う？
To use the power I swore to Crusch-sama,
クルシュ様の
ための力で―
the power I swore to my lady, for this!?
殿下に約束した力で
こんなことを！
（スバル）
ああー バカなバカなー
Ah, it can't be, it can't be...
Just when I'd found such a perfect vessel...
私はこんな
ふさわしき器を前に…
My lack of virtue was what forced this
undesirable decision on you and Ferris.
（ユリウス）
君とフェリスに―
Just when the Ordeal's completion was at hand...
望まぬ決断を強いたのは
私の不徳だ
いずれ
罰を受けるだろう
One day, I'm sure I will get my just deserts.
（スバル）
あー 私が滅ぶことなど…
I will never die...
Nefarious Sloth